# BAWANDEEP SINGH

Mississauga, Ontario | Phone: 647 833-1248 | Email: singhbawan48@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/singhbawan | GitHub: github.com/singhbawan | Portfolio: singhbawan.codes

#### SUMMARY

Full stack developer who likes to create responsive, accessible and visually cohesive web applications utilizing advanced front-end skills and strong programming fundamentals. Earned a certificate from University of Toronto's SCS Coding Boot Camp. Prior to the career as a web developer, spent three years as a Machine Builder, Gaining expertise in project management, communicating effectively with customers and helping customer's to bring their vision to life - skills that have proven to be invaluable as a developer.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages and Frameworks: JavaScript ES6+, CSS, HTML, MySQL, MongoDB, REST, GraphQL, Apollo, Express, React, Redux, Node, JQuery, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Bulma, Tailwind, MUI.

**Applications:** Git, GitHub pages, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas.

**API exposure**: Alpaca, Listen Notes, Geoapify, rickandmortyapi, openweathermap.

## **PROJECTS**

Starship | https://github.com/FOR-TIMI/Starship | https://still-cliffs-68409.herokuapp.com/

- StarShip allows users to track the market in general or search a specific stock. They can check its performance through different visualizations (Dynamic apex charts, web scraping).
- Role: Worked on Alpaca API, Zoomable TimeSeries Line Chart, Candlestick Chart, Treemap Chart, User Verification using stripe, Search Bar and NavBar. GraphQL queries and mutations, schema definition. Hosted team meetings on figma and pair-programmed with teammates to remove blockers.
- Front End: React, MUI. Back End: Express, Node js. Database: MongoDB, GraphQL and Apollo Client.

# Join-Us | https://github.com/nab-man/Join-Us | https://join-us2.herokuapp.com/

- Join-Us allows the user to create events where other users can give their RSVP. Comments can be posted and deleted.
- Tools Used: Express, MySQL, Node, Sequelize, MVC, handlebars, bcrypt and tailwind.

# Reactor | https://github.com/singhbawan/reactor | https://singhbawan.github.io/reactor/

- These are small games that I made to learn more about react.
- Tools Used: react, css, javascript, github pages, html.

## Pods and Parks I https://github.com/AdamGabo/PlayMeSpotify I https://singhbawan.github.io/PlayMeSpotify/

- A Podcast finder website which recommends nearby parks.
- Tools Used: react, css, javascript, github pages, html.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Web Development Certificate:** University of Toronto; Toronto, Ontario (Remote) | **Dec 2022** *A 12 week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills.* 

Electro Mechanical Engineering Technician: Centennial College; Scarborough, Ontario | 2020 Mechatronics and Industrial Automation: Indo-Swiss Training Centre; Chandigarh, India | 2016

### EXPERIENCE

## **Automation and Controls Manager**

May 2021 - Aug 2022

**HPML:** Waterloo, Ontario

**Transferable skills:** Leadership, teamwork, communication, problem solving, coordination, adaptability, patience.

- 100% success rate on project approval by making an Initial concept that covers all bases for client and competitive quotation.
- Performed functions related to project management including 3D-designing, 2D-Drawing, BOM generation, Tracking open PO, Quality Inspection, Assembly, Wiring, PLC programming and Testing.
- Selected to be management representative for Quality Management System. Created multiple documents and obtained ISO certificate 9001:2015.

CNC Technician Oct 2020 - May 2021

**Ckdpack Packaging Inc.:** Mississauga, Ontario

**Transferable skills:** Communication, problem solving, collaboration, coordination, organization.

- Installed fully automatic mask making machine and shrink wrap machine to run production of masks.
- Programmed FANUC ARC Mate welding robot to run multiple batch custom welding jobs.
- Programmed HOMAG CNC router and learned Aspire by Vectric to program the toolpaths.

Electrical Supervisor Aug 2017 - July 2018

HSIIDC: Haryana, India

Transferable skills: Project time management, teamwork, communication, problem solving, an eye for detail.

- Performed troubleshooting of major legacy systems; resolved failures and malfunctions.
- Spearheaded maintenance and repairing functions of Servo motors, controller and amplifiers while identifying and replacing damaged parts.
- Supervised maintenance personnel while inspecting and assessing daily operations performed by the staff; led tender openings for major/minor projects.